# MOHAMMAD HASHEMI

ML ENGINEER









#### SUMMARY

I'm a Machine Learnining Engineer with 4 years of experience and I spent most of my career doing **Computer Vision** projects. My preference is to enhance my skills in various fields (**Machine learning** and **Backend**) and enjoy learning them.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Arooj Company**

Computer Vision Engineer • dec2021 - july2024 - hybrid

#### **Hand Vein Detection Device**

 Preprocess images and create a dataset for training deep learning segmentation models (<u>Unet</u>, <u>Segnet</u>, <u>Yolo</u>,...) with pytorch/tensorflow framework and optimize models to work in real-time with Raspberry Pi.

#### **Shrimp Head Cutter**

- Process shrimp images and detect head shrimp at various angles using equalization and edge detection methods in OpenCV to work
  in real time with high accuracy.
- Implement in Raspberry Pi and test accuracy and time of processing

#### Freelance

2022 - Present - Remote

## **Baby Cry Emotion Detection**

- Customized two CNN models: one to detect if a baby is crying, and another to classify the reason for the crying and reach to 95%
- Api model using FastApi Dockerize

## **ADHD Diagnosis**

- Preprocessed activity data and extracted features using the **signal processing** concepts
- Tested various machine learning algorithms (Random Forest, SVM) with grid search and cross-validation to achieve better accuracy.

#### **Plate Recognition**

• Designed real-time plate detection model using **TensorFlow & Keras** and trained Persian character classification and create api with **Flask** for Mobile App Development.

### **Tomato Leaf Disease Detection**

• Design and optimize deep-learning model based on **CNN** to detect Tomato Leaf Disease to work on embedded systems and mobile applications to work in real time with remarkable accuracy(97%)

#### **Twitter Sentiment Analysis**

Cleaned and preprocessed NLP datasets, performed feature extraction, and trained various classification models (RNN, LSTM,
 Decision Tree) to optimize performance and accuracy in natural language processing tasks.

### **Oral Cancer Diagnosis**

• Design a CNN model for oral cancer diagnosis, increasing accuracy from 78% to 90%

## SKILLS

#### Work with:

- Computer Vision Algorithm
- Deep learning
- Python
- Machine Learning Algorithms

# Experience with: • MATLAB

- MATLAB
- Time Series Forecasting
- API Models (Flask)C++

# Reinforcement Learning Algorithms

- sk) Generative Models
  - Ger
    - Docker

Familliar with:

#### Libraries

- Tensorflow
- Pytorch
- Scikit-Learn
- Pandas
- Numpy
- OpenCV

## EDUCATION

## **Bachelor of electrical engineering**

PGU Bushehr University • 2019-2023